it's looking like
a percentage of people who get coveted
never recover or or
we're only six months in um their
recovery is a lot longer process
and their symptoms sound
and look an awful lot like chronic
fatigue syndrome
myalgic and myologic encephalitis
and therefore if you
are indeed joining our community i need
to offer you some advice
we need to offer you some advice this is
my advice i can't speak for the whole
community
except this is the same advice that
because you're not gonna even seek it
out until it's too late until you've
already listened to your doctors and
they've nearly killed you
so that is the advice do not listen to
your doctors when it comes to this
illness
they do not know what they are talking
about
unless they're giving you the same
advice i'm about to give you which is
do not exercise do not push your body
in any way shape or form do not let your
heart rate
get into cardio don't let your heart
rate get up which is
bad advice for the regular population
that's how you get healthy
for us it is poison for our bodies
and the worst that happens is you listen
to me and then you can push it
later right you recover or you don't and
then you test it and see
if you listen to the doctors you get
worse and worse and you're expected to
ex
to listen to them so then you just keep
thinking okay well i'm not doing it
right
and keep pushing it and pushing it those
are the people
who don't recover or are less likely to
recover
so you have to learn how to pace and
it's an inner no one else can give you
that limit
some people can't can't get out of bed
all day every day
brushing their teeth is like a weekly
activity
most of those people from what i've
experienced are because they didn't
listen in the beginning
to this not to the doctors they listened
to the doctors
do wait for your spoons to be on sale
what does that mean it means waiting
until you have the urge to do an
activity to do an activity
not doing it because you should waiting
until you want to
let your dishes pile up let your laundry
pile up until you want to do it
because pushing yourself through
everything in society says that's what
you're supposed to do
push push push keep going keep going
sleep when you're dead it will kill you
don't do it keep your heart rate low
do not exercise if you do exercise like
i do yoga and i go for a walk now that
i'm years into this experience
and those things fuel my soul and i'm
starting to listen my body's starting to
say okay now you can skip
now you can run now you can do these
things and when i listen in the moment
to my body but this is after years of
calming it down
if you're someone who's constantly go go
go go if you were an
athlete if you were an entrepreneur if
you were any of these things that are
expected to be energetic and out there
doing doing doing
you're gonna maybe need to not listen to
your body when it tells you to do that
until you've learned to calm it down
and then hopefully you can learn to your
inner voice and it does tell you
when you can add stuff back in
it can be a blessing for that very
reason it forces you to listen to your
own inner voice
and it forces you to put your own oxygen
mask on first
to learn what gives you safety
in your in your nervous system and
happiness because if you can find what
brings
safety and happiness that is how you
recover
that is how you heal or that is where
you find beauty
in the acceptance of not healing because
being happy and safe
is a pretty good feeling no matter what
even if you're in pain and fatigued
it's better than the opposite
find the activities that bring you joy
and
allow yourself to spend your limited
spoons on those things
do not push yourself through it
and find the community that's
experienced this
and so that you at least have some peers
so when the doctors are telling you
you're crazy there's at least of like
actually all these people
say the opposite of what you're saying
maybe all of you joining our community
all at the same time because of cobit 19
maybe the doctors catch up and they stop
offering better advice
but that's not happening yet so please
find the chronic fatigue communities
find the myalgic encephalitis
communities
and listen to the people with the lived
experience
thank you